Brody E. Hill

GitHub P: (972) 743 – 3918 E: Brodyhill44@gmail.com Plano, TX LinkedIn

SUMMARY

During my time with Candidate Labs, I observed a gap between data projects and business outcomes, highlighting the critical need to align data initiatives with concrete business goals. Conversations with industry leaders at Google and Microsoft further fueled my passion for ensuring data projects yield explainable and trustworthy results, particularly for non-technical stakeholders. I firmly believe that the principal value of a data professional lies not only in technical proficiency but in the skill to leverage tools like SQL, Python, Tableau, or Excel to drive meaningful change and generate insights that directly impact business success.

EDUCATION

Baylor UniversityWaco, TXBachelor of Business Administration – Deans List all four yearsMay 2019

Springboard

Data Science Fellow – Business Analytics Specialization Track

December Graduation

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Machine Learning: classification, regression, clustering, feature engineering Coding Languages and Top Skills: Python, Excel, <u>Tableau</u>, <u>SQL</u>, <u>Power BI</u>

Python Packages and Skills: Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Pandas, Numpy, Scipy

Analysis Skills: Data Wrangling, Data Visualization, Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Modeling

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Springboard

Data Science Fellow – Business Analytics Specialization Track

May 2023 - Present (December Graduation)

- 600+ active hour, 1000+ study hour data bootcamp focused on building the practical skills needed to thrive as a data analyst / future data scientist.
- Completed 50+ mini projects and three capstone projects, with an intense focus on how to practically apply data science and analytics to concrete and specific business objectives.
- Met with Data Leaders across companies like JP Morgan, Accenture, Google, Microsoft and Walmart to gain a relevant and practical view on how to apply my curriculum to specific business outcomes.

Verifiable Plano, TX (Remote)

Business Development Lead, Oct 2022 - March 2023

- BD lead focused on acquiring new business within the healthcare payor space.
- Set meetings with key accounts such as Blue Cross Blue Shield California, Kaiser Permanente, and Geisinger.
- While my time with Verifiable was short, I achieved 116% of my assigned quota.
- Left to pursue the Springboard Data Science bootcamp.

Candidate Labs Plano, TX (Remote)

Talent Manager, May 2021 - Oct 2022 *Part of 75% reduction in workforce*

- \$1.1M in closed search fees in one calendar year, presidents club winner summer of 2022.
- As the first hire for CL's talent function, I played a key role in building the responsibilities and initial success of the function.
- Sourced, interviewed, and closed key roles (typically director through C level) for clients within the a16z, Sequoia Capital, Battery Ventures, and other tier one VC firms' portfolios.

Gartner Plano, TX (Remote)

Senior Business Development Specialist L3 Jan 2020 - May 2021 (promoted from L2 Jan 2021)

- Focused on installing the Gartner for CFO's product within the State and Local Government Sector.
- Exceed 100% of quota every month I was with Gartner.
- Through LinkedIn outreach, cold emailing, and cold calling, I sat and conducted meetings with CFO's within state and local government agencies across the west coast territory.

SELECTED PROJECTS

Understanding GPU Feature Importance Using Machine Learning

Springboard

- Walked through the entire DS method, from wrangling data in the wild to model implementation.
- Sourced raw data from Google Dataset search, cleaned the data, performed EDA, and modeled the data using scikit-learn.
- Key Skills: Data Wrangling, Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Visualization, ML Modeling.
- Full documentation can be found here.

Predicting Credit Card Fraud Using Machine Learning (In progress)

Springboard

- Using data on 500,000+ credit card transitions from customers in Europe, I'm building a classification model to predict cases of fraud.
- I'll wrangle the raw data from the wild, clean, visualize and explore the data in Python, and model from there.
- Key Skills: Data Wrangling, Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Visualization, ML Modeling.
- You can follow along with my progress and see results here.

An Exercise in Data Story Telling and Visualization

Springboard

- Our projects are only as impactful as we can communicate. Among the most important skills a data professional can possess is the ability to craft data into story that easy to follow and understand, especially among non-technical stakeholders.
- During this exercise, I took a dataset on the nutritional value of Starbucks drinks and crafted a story from it.
- Key Skills: Data Visualization, Data Storytelling, Data Analysis.
- Take a look here.

Using SQL to Gather Key Business Insights

Springboard

- Designed to test my ability to translate business objectives into SQL queries.
- Given a schema and a list of specific questions, I was on my own to get the data I needed to an understandable and usable form.
- Take a look here.